

## Skills

# JavaScript / TypeScript (Expert)

Web, Desktop, and Mobile Applications (React, Vue, Angular, Svelte)

### C# Development (Expert)

Web, Desktop, Server, and Mobile **Applications** 

# APIs (Expert)

GraphQL & REST APIs

### SQL Databases (Proficient)

PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL Server, MariaDB, MySQL, SQLite

#### NoSQL Databases (Proficient) MongoDB, Firebase, Redis

# AWS Lambda, Google Cloud Functions,

DevOps (Competent)

Serverless (Proficient)

**Azure Functions** Edge Computing (Competent)

# Edge Functions & Edge Runtime

Docker, Kubernetes, GitHub Actions, GitLab

### Spoken Languages

## German (native)

English (B2)

### **Denis Knaack**

Software Development & Consulting

& +49 170 5867448 • @ denis@knaack.it • & https://www.knaack.it

### **Profiles**

in /denisknaack

🏄 /dknaack

/knaackee

12/2021 - today

C#

C#

C#

C#

**React Native** 

Figma

**TypeScript** 

**Github Actions** 

Throughout my career, I have worked with various programming languages, tools, and services. My passion for technology motivated me to continually evolve. Customers appreciate my ability to integrate new technologies and provide solutions that often exceed their objectives.

With over 20 years in the field, my passion for technology and innovation has not diminished; it remains as strong as on my very first day.

### **Professional Experience** KNAACK.IT

Freelancing (C#, Node.JS, TypeScript, React, SQL) Steinberg am See, DE

11/2012 - 02/2015 Omniga GmbH & Co. KG

Software Development Professional (C#, SQL, JavaScript) Regensburg, DE 04/2011 - 11/2012 SmilingBits GmbH & Co. KG

Senior Manager Software Development (C#, SQL, JavaScript) Regensburg, DE

01/2008 - 04/2011 SmilingBits GmbH & Co. KG Manager Software Development (C#, SQL, JavaScript) Regensburg, DE

GoNamic GmbH 10/2003 - 01/2008 Manager Software Development (C#, SQL, JavaScript) Regensburg, DE

Education

Distribution)

BSZ Matthäus Runtinger BSIII 2000 - 2003Fachinformatiker Anwendungsentwicklung (IT Specialist in

Application Development)

### Freelance Projects (Excerpt) Fintech Startup

Development of backend solutions and APIs for a fintech startup, utilizing C# and Microsoft SQL Database.

Automated Email Dispatch (Implementation of Automated Invoice Email C#

Implementation of an automated system for emailing invoices, developed in C#.

Visa Policy Update C# Implementation of new requirements for visa payment processing using C#.

Website Relaunch C#

Redevelopment and modernization of a website using C#.

**Password Validation** C# Transition from plain text passwords to hashed and salted passwords,

implemented in C#.

Implementation and documentation.

Advising a development team on GraphQL implementation and best practices.

Mailgun Integration

Consulting GraphQL

Plug-In System

**COVID Scanner App** 

TypeScript.

uı / ux

application, utilizing NodeJS.

developed in TypeScript.

CI / CD

implemented using NodeJS and TypeScript.

NodeJS / Typescript GraphQL Backend

Development of a sample implementation for a GraphQL backend using NodeJS and TypeScript.

**NNTP Client** 

Development of an NNTP client using C#. C#

Enhancement of a Windows client with a plug-in system, developed in C#. Auto-Updater

Implementation of an automatic update system for a Windows application.

Creation of an app for scanning and displaying information from QR codes, developed with React Native.

Marketing Website React / TypeScript

React / TypeScript Al Chatbot

Development of a website for a mid-sized company, utilizing React and

Design and integration of an AI chatbot based on ChatGPT, implemented using React and TypeScript.

Creation and presentation of a user interface for a web application using

Figma.

**NodeJS** Automatic Update Feature for Electron App Development of a self-updating mechanism tailored for an Electron

NodeJS / TypeScript GraphQL Backend

Development of an API with integration to a PostgreSQL database,

**Chrome Extension** 

TypeScript.

**Outlook Plugin** TypeScript Creation of a plugin for easier management of filters and folders in Outlook,

Development of a Chrome extension with ChatGPT integration, implemented in

**Desktop Client** NodeJS / Electron / TypeScript

Development of a cross-platform client for Windows, Mac, and Linux for

processing and analyzing AAF files, using NodeJS, Electron, TypeScript, and C#.

Creation and implementation of a Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) process for a team with various projects, utilizing GitHub

Actions. React / TypeScript **Progressive Web App** 

Development of a Progressive Web App (installable, offline-ready) with

features including authentication, email sending, and more, built using React and TypeScript.